Guide to the Carolyn Burke Collection on Mina Loy and Lee Miller
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- July 2013 Acquisition, 7.5; (18 boxes)
  - Carolyn Burke Research Files on Lee Miller
    - Horst, Horst P., 1996-1997
    - Man Ray: Electricite, 2000-2001, undated
    - New York studies from 1932-1934, undated
    - Four Saints, 2000-2000
    - Picasso, Pablo in the 1950s, undated
    - Penrose, Tony: Birth, undated
    - Penrose, Roland: Wedding in 1947, undated
    - Beaton, Cecil, undated
    - Vogue (UK) and Clifford Coffin, 1997, undated
    - Holocaust photography research, 1996, 1999, undated
    - Liberated Paris: Conditions and Vogue people, 1942-1942
    - Levy, Julien and Joseph Cornell, 1993-1998
    - Penrose, Roland, 1995-1998
    - Summer of 1937 and Pablo Picasso, undated
    - Picasso Museum: Lee Miller, Roland Penrose, and Pablo Picasso, undated (Box 13)
    - Picasso, Pablo and Lee Miller, 1998, undated
    - Miller, Lee: St. Malo, undated
    - Agar, Eileen, undated
    - Egypt: Interviews, 1996-2002
    - Roumette, Sylvain: Film and interviews, undated
    - Balmary, Marie: Interviews, 1998-1998
    - Miller family: Interviews and correspondence, 1992-1999
    - Poughkeepsie, 1997, undated
    - Bardavon and Jesse Effron, 1994-1999
    - Poughkeepsie: Carolyn Burke trip, 1998-1998
    - Poughkeepsie: Carolyn Burke trip, 1999-1999
    - Feierabend, Miriam "Minnow", 1999-1999
    - Miller, Erik, 1992, 1998
    - Miller, John, 1996-1999
    - Ramm, Tanja and Margit Rowell, 1997-2000
    - de l'Ecotais, Emmanuelle: Man Ray and Lee Miller, 1999-2000
    - Liberman, Alexander and Francine du Plessix Gray, 1996-1996
    - Leivick, Jody: Kodak and stereoscope, 2000-2000
    - Jacobs, Lisa, 1997-1997
    - Foresta, Merry: Man Ray, Lee Miller, and Seabrook, 1999-2000
    - Abbott, Bernice, 1978-2001
    - New York interviews, transcribed, 1998-2000
    - Penrose, Tony, 1999-1999
    - Richardson, John, 1999-1999
    - Scherman, David, 1996-2001
    - Hamilton, Nina and Auxiliary Territorial Service (ATS), 1985, 1997, undated
    - Miller, Lee: War photography, 2000, undated
    - Scherman, David: Family, 1996-1999
    - Perrussel, Raymond, 2001-2001
    - Charles-Roux, Edmonde and Doctor Dubourg, 1998-2002
    - Dunn, Warren: Interview and 42nd Division at Dachau, 1999-1999 (Box 14)
    - Riordan, Tom and Dan Dougherty and Felix Sparks on the 45th Division at Dachau, 1995-2002
    - Messinesi, Despina and Rosamund Bernier on Suisse Post-War, 1996-1998
    - Dachau: Arie van Soest and Jacques Hindermeyer, 1996, undated
    - Miller, Lee: Recipes, undated
    - Dachau: History and bibliography, undated
    - Liberators of Dachau and Buchenwald, undated
    - Interviews, 1996, 1999, 2001
    - Paris: Interviews, 1996-2001
    - Hare, David, 2001-2002
    - Burke, Carolyn: Correspondence, 1997, 2004
    - Jacobs, Lisa, 1997, 1999
    - Burke, Carolyn: Correspondence in United States, 1992-1999
    - Burke, Carolyn: Correspondence in United Kingdom, 1996-2002
    - Interviews in United States, 1996-1999
    - Carrington, Leonora, 1999-2001
    - Gascoyne, David and English Surrealists, 1997, undated
    - Morris, John G., 1998, undated
    - Deriaz, Diane, 1988, undated
    - Carrington, Leonora, 1999-1999
    - Tanning, Dorothea, 1997-2005
    - Miller, Theodore: Photographs, Poughkeepsie, and Trish Taylor, undated
    - Miller family photographs, duplicates, undated
    - Balmary, Marie, 1998-1998
    - Photographs of Lee Miller, duplicates, 1975-2004
    - Penrose, Tony: Interviews, 1992-1999 (Box 15)
    - Bourgin, Si: Regarding photographs, 2004-2004
    - Roumette, Sylvain, 1997-1997
    - Carson, Josephine, 2000, undated
    - Fraser, Kathleen, 1991-1998
    - Miller, Lee: Photographs in museum collections and Renee Devine, 2001-2001
    - Miller, Lee: Exhibitions, 1990-2008
    - Getty Research Institute, 2000-2000
    - Tate notes, 1996-1996
    - Miller, Lee: Aesthetic and Juno Gemes, undated
    - Picture Post (1940-1950), 1999, undated
    - Cookery of the 1950s, 1952, undated
    - Miller, Lee: Vogue lists, 1998, undated
    - Minotaure, undated
    - Scherman, David and Life, undated
    - Miller, Lee: Photograph sales, 1996, 2004
    - Miller, Lee: What They See in Cinema (1956), undated
    - Lee Miller: A Life, Notes and Related Papers
      - Illustrations: Chapters 1-3, undated
      - Illustrations: Chapters 4-6, undated
      - Illustrations: Chapters 7-9, undated
      - Illustrations: Chapters 11-13, undated
      - Illustrations: Chapters 14-16, undated
      - Illustrations: Chapters 17-18, undated
      - Illustrations in text: Personal, 2004
      - Chapter titles, undated
      - Introduction, undated
      - Chapters 1-3: Text and notes, 1919, 2000, undated (Box 16)
      - Chapter 4: New York 1926-1929 notes, 1999-2000, undated
      - Chapter 5: Notes and text, 1997-2000, undated
      - Chapters 6-7: Notes, 1992-2000, undated
      - Chapters 11-13: Notes, 1942-1943, 2000, undated
      - Chapter 13: Margaret Bourke-White and Lee Miller German pictures, undated
      - Chapters 14-16: Notes, 1961, 1998-2003, undated
        Includes notes for associated chapters, as well as two typed letters, signed, from Julien Levy to Joella Bayer about Lee Miller and Roland Penrose, dated 1961.
      - Chapters 17-18: Notes, 1970, 2000-2003, undated
        Includes notes for associated chapters, as well as an autograph letter, signed from Lee Miller to Theodore Miller, dated 1970.
      - Afterword, undated
      - Acknowledgements, undated
      - Insert 1: Paris, New York, and Egypt, undated
      - Insert 2: War, undated
      - Insert 3: Portraits, undated
      - Bibliography, 2004, undated
      - Copied notes and Knopf form, 2004, undated
      - Flap copy and insert layouts, 2005-2005
      - Chapters 1-3: Page proofs, 2005-2005 (Box 17)
      - Chapters 3-7: Page proofs, 2005-2005
      - Chapters 8-12: Page proofs, 2005-2005
      - Chapters 13-17: Page proofs, 2005-2005
      - Chapter 18, Appendix, Notes, and Acknowledgments: Page proofs, 2005-2005
      - Index: Notes and typescript, undated
      - Chapters 1-4: Typescript, corrected, undated
      - Chapters 5-9: Typescript, corrected, undated
      - Chapters 10-14: Typescript, corrected, undated
      - Chapters 15-18 and Acknowledgment: Typescript, corrected, undated
      - Notes: Typescript, corrected, undated
  - Audiovisual Material
    - Mina Loy
      - Interviews for Becoming Modern, 1977-1978, undated
        5 audiocassette tapes.
        - Le Savoureux, Madame Henri, 1977-1977 (Box 19)
        - Blackburn, Paul, undated
        - Lindsay, Robert, 1978-1978 (Box 20)
      - Italia Futurista microfilm, circa 2008 (Box 18)
      - Haweis, Stephen: Memoir microfilm, undated
    - Lee Miller
      - Interviews and research, 1937-2001 (Box 20)
        16 audiocassettes.
      - Documentaries and research, undated (Box 18)
        4 VHS cassettes.
  - Restricted Fragile
    - Lee Miller
      - Interviews and research, undated (Box 21)
        3 3.5" floppy disks and 1 DVD.